<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Learning on Keiththomps</title>
    <link>https://keiththomps.github.io/categories/learning/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Learning on Keiththomps</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://keiththomps.github.io/categories/learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Recovering from Poor Planning</title>
      <link>https://keiththomps.github.io/2016/02/08/recovering-from-poor-planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2016 12:04:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keiththomps.github.io/2016/02/08/recovering-from-poor-planning/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;My goal of reading one book a week didn&amp;#8217;t make it that far without a few hiccups. Reading &lt;em&gt;Good to Great&lt;/em&gt; took me a day longer than I was expecting and the book I had scheduled to follow that was a pretty big technical book. I was unable to finish reading all of &lt;em&gt;Programming Elixir&lt;/em&gt; within the week that I allotted for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;poor-planning-of-a-good-goal&#34;&gt;Poor Planning of a Good Goal&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Normally, this would be the point where people would throw in the towel on a New Year&amp;#8217;s resolution because they&amp;#8217;ve already &amp;#8220;failed&amp;#8221;, but it shows me that I did a poor job of planning a reasonable goal. I&amp;#8217;m not the fastest reader by nature (I subvocalize, and I tend to get distracted and need to re-read passages), so 1 book a week would be fine if I only planned on reading books that we  small. That&amp;#8217;s not what I&amp;#8217;m actually going for, I want to read 52 books in a year. Some books will take me longer than others, and I shouldn&amp;#8217;t be concerned by that unless I get to the point where I can&amp;#8217;t possibly read 52 books by December 31, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s important to set &lt;em&gt;good&lt;/em&gt; goals and the way that I worded my reading goal set me up for failure. If I chose to read something that got me out of my comfort zone there was a good chance it would take longer than a week, so I&amp;#8217;m adjusting the wording of my goal to be this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will read 52 books in a year, &lt;em&gt;averaging&lt;/em&gt; 1 book per week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>