<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal on Keiththomps</title>
    <link>http://keiththomps.com/categories/personal/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal on Keiththomps</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://keiththomps.com/categories/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking a Look at My Life Turns</title>
      <link>http://keiththomps.com/2015/10/11/my-testimony/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2015 10:58:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://keiththomps.com/2015/10/11/my-testimony/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;At church, we’ve been talking about how our own stories matter. Each one of us has a story that is unique and telling that story is one of the greatest things that we can do. By telling our own stories, we give others the chance to learn from our past experiences or to wonder about something that they’ve never experienced. As a church, we’ve been digging into what makes a good story (literarily speaking). We took some time to look at points in our lives where the plot jumps or changes direction, which we’re calling &lt;em&gt;life turns&lt;/em&gt;. I’m going to go over a few of the significant &lt;em&gt;life turns&lt;/em&gt; to build up my story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;comprehending-death&#34;&gt;Comprehending Death&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first time something or someone dies in the life of a child it always seems to be a toss up as how the child will react. For me, I can remember being sad and crying when my grandmother died when I was four or five, but it didn’t affect me as much as it should have because I just didn’t understand. The first death that I experienced that affected me as I would expect was when my Uncle Victor (Vic for short) died. I was in the fifth grade at the time, and up to this point I would say I was a pretty well-adjusted kid, but probably a little emotional. I remember crying a lot about things that weren’t that important. I was close to my Uncle Vic and when he died I felt so horrible that I hated God for allowing this to happen and set out to protect myself from feeling this type of pain again. From this point, I became a cold child. I tried my best to guard my emotions against others, and this eventually lead to me becoming cruel to those around me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was the first significant &lt;em&gt;life turn&lt;/em&gt; that I could recall. A real change in who I was, and there was no going back. This was a negative turn that would result in a few problematic situations and damaged relationships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;meeting-a-positive-influence&#34;&gt;Meeting a Positive Influence&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same year that my first &lt;em&gt;life turn&lt;/em&gt; occurred I was fortunate enough to get to know my best friend James. On his own, James is a wonderful man and has always been a great influence on me, but when we became friends I got much more than a single friend. His entire family took me in like I was one of them. This lead to me becoming the “adopted” son, not because I didn’t have my own family, but because I spent a lot of time there and James’s parent poured a lot of their love and guidance into me. George and Kathy Brake loved God in a way that I had never seen before. I didn’t understand it at first, but it didn’t take long before some of that started to rub off on me. George took the time to lead a youth group at the Brake house each week and I tagged along because it was an excuse to hang out with James. That’s how it started. This group that my friend’s dad lead was the bridge that lead me to know God. Every since then the Brake family has welcomed me with open arms, and I continue to grow as a follower of Christ because of them. This was one of the most positive &lt;em&gt;life turns&lt;/em&gt; that has occurred in my life thus far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tragically, George Brake died in a car accident a few weeks ago, but his wisdom lives on in his children and his effect on the world is not hard to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;loved-and-lost&#34;&gt;Loved and Lost&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving forward into my first year of college, I had grown up and dated the same girl all through high school. I’m not a huge planner, but I thought I could see where my life was going. I imagined myself finishing my math degree, becoming an actuary, and marrying my high school sweetheart. None of that happened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During my freshman year of college, I had something that I didn’t have while growing up, friends that were nearby for me to hang out with. Growing up in a town of fifty people I only had one boy my age that I could hang out with, and he and I had a tendency to argue and not speak for months at a time. I lived in an all-Freshman dorm my first year and became good friends with the other guys on my floor. I got way too caught up in having friends and let my relationship with God suffer. At this same time, my girlfriend was not falling away from God, but instead growing stronger. This eventually caused her to leave me, and I didn’t even see it coming. In true Keith (or rather human) fashion, something horrible happened in my life so I turned on God with my full fury. This time I didn’t just shout at the sky, though, I started going after the Christians that my girlfriend hung out with. I like to think I was trying to figure out what went wrong, but that’s really not the case. I’m a pretty intelligent person and at this point in my life I used this in the worst possible way. I poked holes in the faith of the Christians I ran into, and I did this in the most hurtful way I could. If I had to relate to anyone in the Bible at this point it would be Saul. I persecuted Christians with ruthless abandon. This is the most shameful of my &lt;em&gt;life turns&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;end-it&#34;&gt;End It&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having a four and a half year relationship fall apart isn’t the best situation, and I didn’t handle it well. Besides being wrathful, I was also depressed. This depression built up until I eventually decided that it was too much. One evening as I was driving back to Toledo I decided that I should just end my life. I’m not one for gore and I didn’t want people to know that I intentionally killed myself, so I decided a car accident was probably my best choice. I was driving down the highway going somewhere between 90-100 mph waiting for the next overpass so I could swerve into the support column when I decided that I needed a little music. At this point I didn’t listen to Christian music, but that’s what I ended up on and the song that was on spoke to me more directly than I had ever experienced (sadly I can’t remember the song). Needless to say, that was enough to stop me from being as stupid as I had planned. I broke down crying and felt more loved at that moment than I can explain. This was a pretty positive &lt;em&gt;life turn&lt;/em&gt; by not being the end of the story. I realized that I didn’t have the relationship that I expected to have, but God still loved me very much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-new-journey&#34;&gt;A New Journey&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shortly after not committing suicide Summer break started and I had a summer job lined up to work for Central Insurance. Central had given me a large scholarship so I seemed like a shoe-in for a position, but I would have never considered trying if it hadn’t been for my ex-girlfriend’s mom suggesting it. From where I stand now it’s interesting to see how the story unfolded and all it took to get me to Central, where my next &lt;em&gt;life turn&lt;/em&gt; happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few weeks of working at this job, I got to meet the actuarial intern who also worked in my department part time. Her name was Kendra. She and I got along well and we both had the same career direction. The first time we hung out after work was the day that she got her wisdom teeth taken out. She looked and sounded incredibly silly, but I enjoyed every moment we got to spend together. Things were looking up for me at this point, I was finally letting myself be happy again. To make a long story short, she and I started dating before we both went back to college, had a long distance relationship (2.5 hours apart), and eventually got engaged. The distance was hard, but Kendra was able to use it help me not rely on her for my happiness, this lead me to grow closer to God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;money-can-make-you-look-stupid&#34;&gt;Money Can Make You Look Stupid&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After Kendra had graduated from college and moved home I was still in Toledo, but wanted to be closer to home since I wasn’t getting anything out of college. Prior to this, I had made some stupid mistakes with money and built up a large debt unknowingly. I’m not going to go into a ton of detail because I wrote most of my thoughts on money &lt;a href=&#34;http://keiththomps.com/personal/make-a-budget.md&#34;&gt;over here&lt;/a&gt;, but it embarrassed me to discover my own stupidity. This embarrassment made it hard for me to admit what I had done to Kendra. Eventually, I tried to transfer from UT to IPFW so that I could live at home and be closer to Kendra. I thought I had everything worked out with the transfer, but I was only given in-state tuition for IPFW if I went to school full-time which I was not planning on doing since I was consulting full-time. I put all of my eggs in one basket and ruined my chances of graduating in a timely fashion from UT by dropping some courses before finalizing my transfer to IPFW. At this point, I needed to tell Kendra what had happened, and it terrified me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I sat down and talked to Kendra about the mistakes I had made regarding school and money she nearly left me. I was hiding things from her because I was ashamed and that’s not something we could build a healthy marriage on. Thankfully, she showed forgiveness and helped me to get my personal finances under control. This education on finances set me on a good track and really changed my life, but the forgiveness and mercy she showed are the incredible parts about this &lt;em&gt;life turn&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;life-theme&#34;&gt;Life Theme&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our stories are more than the turns. Together these turns make up the narrative of our lives. When I step back and look at mine this is the story that I see:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No matter how many times I turn my back, God still finds a way to bring me back to him and show me his love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My turns show the ebb and flow of my life, I make a mistake and God finds a way to put me on the path to redemption. That’s really how I see God working all the time. To sum up everything I know about God is to say that he loves us a lot and no matter how many times we screw up he’ll always be there to guide us and receive us when we decide to return home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s your story?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Budget to See Your Values</title>
      <link>http://keiththomps.com/2014/01/12/budget-see-values/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2014 00:48:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://keiththomps.com/2014/01/12/budget-see-values/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;After a hectic few months of being married (since Oct 26), my wife and I finally&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sat down to write out our budget. I get a lot of comfort out of having a budget&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and feeling like I’m incontrol of my money. This was not my first time making a&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;budget, but it made me think about how budgeting has really changed my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s shown me what I apparently care about and allowed me to adjust accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;who-needs-a-budget-&#34;&gt;Who needs a budget?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Growing up I was always considered a “smart” kid. I took great&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;pleasure in this and thought pretty highly of myself. When I was a junior in&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;high school I was making roughly $300/week. Being as I grew up in the middle of&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;nowhere in Ohio this was a pretty substantial amount of money. I saved none of&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;this money. I had always been a little over confident about college, &lt;em&gt;knowing&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;even in junior high that I would get a full-ride to college, so why did I need&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;to save money? Thankfully, I had been correct and my scholarships would pay for&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;college. I didn’t need a budget, money was going to find it’s way into my bank&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;account…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;loans-aren-t--em-that--em--bad...&#34;&gt;Loans aren’t &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; bad…&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In college I was able to see that I was really lucky that I didn’t need to pay&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;for any of my schooling, but it quickly became apparent that I didn’t have&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;enough money for everything. I had a Summer where I lived off of rice and an&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;occasional egg, but I hadn’t taken out a loan so I was feeling pretty good about&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;that. I didn’t tell my parents that I was struggling, the only person that knew&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;was my girlfriend at the time (now wife). She was pretty concerned for my health&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and loaned me some money against my will. After some persuading, I decided that&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it wouldn’t be a big deal if I took out a small loan in the short term to cover&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;living expenses since I knew I would be getting my first paid internship in a&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;few months. So began my reign of stupidity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;where-s-this-money-coming-from--who-cares.&#34;&gt;Where’s this money coming from? Who cares.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shortly after that I had gotten my first programming job which payed $14/hr,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;which wasn’t too bad and I could pretty easily pay for my living expenses with&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;that type of income. That’s the key right there, I had enough to cover &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; of&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;my expenses at that point without any loan other than the small one that I had&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;taken out when I had no job. I proceeded to not cancel that loan… each&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;semester more money would just pour into my bank account and I didn’t even care&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;where it was coming from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;full-ride---22k-in-debt&#34;&gt;Full-Ride = 22k in debt&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After those few years were finished I ended up having $22,000 in debt. I was so&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ashamed that it nearly broke up my relationship with my fiancée, who just so&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;happens to have a degree in finance. Thankfully, as part of what we thought we&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;should do before we got married we read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/0785289089/&#34;&gt;The Total Money Makeover&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;together and she helped me make my first budget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Telling each and every dollar that came in where to go was a very freeing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;experience. She laughs sometimes to see the change that this has made in me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Budgeting seems obvious to me now and I question people who don’t think about&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it. I sometimes forget that I was one of those people just a year ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;redemption&#34;&gt;Redemption&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having now been on a budget for a year, I’m amazed at how different I feel and&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;act. I used to blow tons of money on things that were simply for entertainment,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;even though I had plenty to do and never did anything good with my money. I’ve&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;since cut down my spending to the lowest it’s ever been and Kendra and I are&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;knocking out our debt faster than we really thought possible. We’re also able to&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;give generously to people and causes that actually need it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jesus states in &lt;strong&gt;Luke 12:34:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For where your treasure is, there your heart will be also.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is completely true. If you’re not in control of you’re money how can you be&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;in control of your heart?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;getting-started&#34;&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For anyone who would like to start budgeting I would definitely recommend&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;reading &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/0785289089/&#34;&gt;Dave Ramsey’s book&lt;/a&gt;. This book really helped me to just&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;understand money as a thing and was a big inspiration. If you’re not really one&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;for books or you’ve already read it, then I would suggest grabbing the&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://a248.e.akamai.net/f/1611/26335/9h/dramsey.download.akamai.com/23572/daveramsey.com/media/pdf/forms/fpu_monthly_cash_flow_plan_forms.pdf&#34;&gt;monthly cash-flow plan&lt;/a&gt; that he provides and start writting out your budget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re on the Mac I’ve translated this into a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dropbox.com/sh/i8wbr0iirb4m6q0/k4a725gG7C/Ramsey-Monthly-Budget.numbers&#34;&gt;Numbers spreadsheet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;that will handle the calculations for you (Kendra and I use this).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you use that spreadsheet, I would encourage you to fill it&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;out and then save it as a template so you can create one for each month and&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;start from scratch with a blank set of transactions. Good luck!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>